<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name></name>
		<update version="0.0.112">
			<file name="starwars-items-wondrous.xml" url="https://github.com/CorrTerek/corr-homebrew-collection/raw/main/corr-homebrew-collection/items/starwars-items-wondrous.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
    
    <element name="R.T.A. Drone" type="Magic Item" source="Star Wars 5e" id="ID_SW5E_MAGIC_ITEM_RTA_DRONE">
        <description>
            <p>This miniature drone is 2 inches long and whirs with the hum of tiny repulsorlifts. You can tap the drone twice as a bonus action. When you do, the drone begins to hover 5 feet in the air. The drone has AC 10 and 10 hit points and flies in this way until a creature grasps it or it falls to 0 hit points. If you move more than 60 feet from the hovering drone, it follows you until it is within 60 feet of you. It takes the shortest route to do so. If prevented from moving, the drone sinks gently to the ground and becomes inactive, and its light fades out. While it's flying, you can use a bonus action to speak its command word to cause it to move up to 20 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you are within 60 feet of the drone, you can speak another command word as an action to cause it to emit the light spell or cast faerie fire (save DC 13), affecting a 20-foot cube originating from itself. Faerie fire does not require concentration when cast in this way, but ends early if the drone falls to 0 hit points. Once the drone casts the faerie fire spell, it can't cast it again until the next dawn.</p>
            <p class="indent">The drone is considered a magical object and is not a creature. If the mending spell is cast on it while it has at least 1 hit point, it regains 2d6 hit points. If the drone falls to 0 hit points, it can't be used again until 2 days have passed, at which point it regains all its hit points.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

</elements>